So, how do you define hypothesis?
Usually, you define them like this. And
you will see at the the end you can do
this with AI. It will help you and it
will give you examples if you give it
the right context.
Um
and they should be not very high level.
So, you should deep dive onto the
hypothesis. So, of course, your big
solution and big problem are the ones
from your pitch, but when you deep dive
on what features you're going to put
there, you will uh see that you need to
validate the tiniest hypothesis. So, if
you're building something for the blind,
you need to demonstrate that the blind
I don't know want to use that tool in
general
and that they will know how to use it,
that they need it, that they will pay
for it, that they will pay $100 a month
or they will pay $10. Those are all all
hypotheses. So, everything you think
about at the moment are hypotheses. So,
hypotheses are looking like that. So,
our proposed solution solves a problem
with the solution.
And they are testable. They are clear.
So, testable means that you can go in an
interview with a user with a set of
questions that validate or invalidate
your hypothesis. And at the end you can
say, yes, it is definitely validated or
definitely invalidated. Because if you
go there just to validate it, you're
lying to yourself. So, and they should
be clear, they should be
specific.
And they can be about the product. So,
what to put in the product. They can be
about the customer, like I don't know,
blind people need something. About the
channel. So, I need to do this on web,
on mobile, omni channel. I need to do it
in a prompt. I don't know. About
pricing, how much it should cost, how
much they would pay. So, if I give you a
very fast-forward example, uh uh a lot
of people assume that students will pay
for something. Students won't pay for
something. So, because they don't have
money. They don't have their own money.
So, they won't pay for anything. We also
have the markets. So, what market you
are uh moving towards.
Um and we also have the competition. So,
you assume that the competition is
building something
uh because of something, whatever. You
need to validate that
uh hypothesis. Also, you can check
feasibility.
Um so, can we actually do it?
Uh do they want it? Or uh should we do
it? And you after that, after putting
all of these uh
hypotheses and counting them,
you can put them on this risk risk
assumption matrix. Because sometimes,
you cannot prove all of your hypotheses.
Therefore, maybe you have no evidence
for them, and they're quite important.
So, that's one. But, even though you
don't have evidence,
you mark them here, and you move ahead
without having evidence, but you take
the risk in the future that this might
not pay off.
If you have evidence and they're
important, you put them in that area and
you mark them there. And this is quite
useful
to know
where you are investing everything.
Because if everything is important and
you have no evidence for it, then you
shouldn't do it. Because then you are
working on something that you have no
evidence against, and it's uh
not worth it, maybe. You will find out
that you need to talk to customers.
That's very important. Maybe you didn't
do this before. Most probably, you
didn't. And it is hard. But, you need to
do it because otherwise, you are not
building you might not build the right
product for them, and you want them to
pay for it.